President Truman will be here tomorrow, so all you folks in Dallas turn out.
Le président Truman arrive demain. Gens de Dallas, venez nombreux.
This is Cowboy Rhythms on KTRN, Wichita Falls.
Ici Cow-boys en chansons, à Wichita Falls.
Here's Hank Williams' big hit tune, "Cold, Cold Heart."
Le tube de Hank Williams, "Cold, Cold Heart".
You ain't ever gonna amount to nothing.
T'arriveras jamais à rien.
Already spent a dime this morning, ain't even had a decent breakfast.
T'as même pas mangé, et t'as déjà claqué 10 cents.
Give me the chalk.
Donne-moi cette craie.
Why don't you comb your hair, Sonny?
File-toi un coup de peigne, Sonny. T'es tout ébouriffé.
I'm surprised you had the nerve to show up…
T'as du culot de te pointer,
… after that stomping you all took last night.
après la pile que t'as prise hier.
- Could've been worse. - Yeah.
Y a pire.
You can say that about nearly everything, I guess.
C'est vrai pour n'importe quoi.
A few football teams have had some luck with tackling.
Y a des équipes qui savent plaquer.
Keeps the other team from scoring quite so often.
Ça empêche les autres de marquer.
Sounds too rough for me.
Trop brutal pour moi.
You don't even care if it was your last game.
Tu te fiches de savoir si tu rejoueras.
You ain't ever gonna get stomped for your own high-school ball team again.
Tu te feras plus piétiner pour ton équipe, c'est sûr.
- Where's your school spirit? - Don't know.
- Tu défends plus ton lycée ? - Sais pas.
You working today?
- Tu bosses aujourd'hui ? - On graisse le camion.
So, you see, this is what I get for betting on my own hometown ball team.
Voilà ce que je gagne à parier pour l'équipe locale.
I ought to have better sense.
Je devrais avoir plus de jugeote.
Wouldn't hurt if you had a better hometown.
Ou habiter une meilleure ville.
You mind pointing that at the floor till I get by?
Tu veux bien baisser cette queue ?
I don't want my eye poked out.
J'ai pas envie que tu me crèves l'œil.
Don't let Billy get too far away, will you, son?
Laisse pas Billy aller trop loin.
You're damn more dangerous in a pool hall than you are on a football field.
T'es plus dangereux au billard que sur un terrain de foot.
You ever heard of tackling?
Le plaquage, ça te dit rien ?
Hey, Duane!
Duane !
Boy, I froze my ass last night!
Je me suis pelé les fesses, hier !
Toss me one!
Lance !
Look, Larry, they can catch.
Ils savent attraper.
Feisty sons of bitches, aren't they? Wish they could tackle.
Ils ont du cran. S'ils savaient plaquer !
Or do something useful.
Ou faire un truc potable.
Team wasn't worth a kiss-my-ass this year.
L'équipe valait pas un clou, cette année.
Fade out, Crawford. One more time.
Encore une fois, Crawford !
All right, you boys. Cut it out.
Arrêtez, les gars.
I got enough problems without you playing that game over again.
J'ai assez de problèmes comme ça.
We could've run off to Mexico with this, you know.
On aurait pu finir au Mexique.
- Hey, play the new one we heard. - Which one?
- Mets la nouvelle. - Laquelle ?
Down payment on breakfast.
Un acompte. Laisse le juke-box aux riches.
Nobody prosperous would eat here.
Les riches mangent pas ici.
You want the pickup first tonight?
Tu veux le camion en prem' ?
I oughtn't get it first every Saturday. It's half yours.
C'est pas juste, c'est toujours moi.
- Go ahead. - You sure?
- Vas-y. - T'es sûr ?
Sure, I'm sure. Anyways, I got lots of deliveries to make.
J'ai des tas de livraisons à faire.
- And I have to go clear to Ranger. - Okay.
Je dois aller jusqu'à Ranger.
I'll be lucky to get back for the second show.
J'aurai du bol si j'arrive pour la 2e séance.
My goodness, Sonny.
Bonté divine, Sonny !
Frank oughtn't work you so late on weekends.
Tu devrais pas travailler si tard.
That's what I keep telling him.
J'arrête pas de lui dire.
You ain't got in in time to see the comedy in three weeks.
T'as pas pu voir un film en entier depuis 3 semaines.
Hope you don't want popcorn, because there ain't none.
Me demande pas de pop-corn, y en a plus.
And you missed the newsreel too.
T'as loupé les actualités.
The main show's done started, so I'll just charge you 30 cents.
Et aussi le début du film, alors 30 cents seulement.
Thanks, Miss Mosey.
Merci.
I was wondering if my daughter had deserted us too, when I heard her voice.
Je croyais ma fille partie, quand j'ai entendu sa voix.
Kay was our only daughter.
Notre seule fille.
I know a father's not supposed to have favourites, but when it's Kay….
Un père ne devrait pas avoir de préférés, mais Kay…
- You smell good. - You like it?
- Tu sens bon. - Tu aimes ?
- What's that? - An atomiser.
- C'est quoi ? - Un atomiseur.
What'd you get? A present?
Un cadeau ?
Who from?
De qui ?
Somebody.
De quelqu'un.
I decided you had a wreck.
Je croyais que tu t'étais viandé.
What's happened to you? You look different.
Tu n'es pas comme d'habitude.
- I do? - Yeah.
Moi ?
You look all lit up inside.
Tu es rayonnante.
You're not wearing your usual deadpan look.
Tu n'as pas cet air renfermé
That "How'd I ever get into this family?" look.
qui semble dire : "Quelle famille !"
Father.
Père !
You've been taking those vitamins Dr Gray sent you.
Tu prends les vitamines du Dr Gray !
That's right.
Oui.
I guess I'll get me some of those vitamins.
Je crois que je vais en prendre aussi.
I'll get it, Delilah.
J'y vais, Delilah.
What's the matter with her? She looks kind of queer.
Qu'a-t-elle donc ? Elle est bizarre.
- Guess what. - What?
Devine.
- It's our anniversary.
C'est notre anniversaire.
We've been going steady a year tonight.
Ce soir, ça fait un an qu'on sort ensemble.
Seems like a lot longer.
Moi, j'aurais dit plus.
You should've got me some anniversary present.
Tu aurais dû me faire un cadeau.
You can have another stick of gum. That's all I got on me.
Un autre chewing-gum. C'est tout ce que j'ai.
You can give me a dollar too.
Donne-moi 1 $.
That's how much it cost me and Marlene for the show.
C'est le prix des billets à moi et à Marlene.
Hi. What are y'all doing back here in the dark?
Qu'est-ce que vous faites dans le noir ?
- He's coming for me in a few minutes. - I'll get your coffee.
Il viendra me chercher.
- Where'd the boys go? - Ben had some date.
- Où sont les garçons ? - Ben est sorti.
Tommy went for basketball practice.
Tommy est au basket.
I don't see why they should get the pickup first all the time.
Je vois pas pourquoi ils ont toujours le camion avant nous.
All they ever wanna do is neck anyway.
En plus, ils font que se bécoter.
Buckley says that's not too young for them to marry.
Buckley dit qu'ils ne sont pas trop jeunes pour se marier.
- I didn't marry your mother till I was 25. - Oh, I know, Pop.
- Je n'ai épousé ta mère qu'à 25 ans. - Je sais, papa.
- Need some help, Jessie? - Yeah, sure do.
- Un coup de main ? - Volontiers.
- So long, Sam. - Bye, Sam.
Salut, Sam.
- Good night. Sure did like the picture. - Well, good.
- J'ai bien aimé le film. - Tant mieux.
Crack your window. Leave the motor running.
Remonte la vitre, laisse tourner le moteur. Ça caille ici.
Your hands are like ice!
T'as les mains glacées !
Put on my gloves.
Je mets mes gants ?
What's the matter with you? You act plain bored.
Qu'est-ce que t'as ? T'as l'air de te raser.
Quit! Quit!
Arrête !
You said this was our anniversary.
C'est notre anniversaire, non ?
Let's do something different.
Fêtons ça autrement.
Well, I like that! You cheapskate.
Ça, c'est la meilleure ! Radin !
Didn't even get me a present, and now you wanna get me pregnant.
Tu m'as pas fait de cadeau et tu veux me mettre enceinte ?
My God, Charlene! It was just my hand.
Bon sang, c'était que ma main !
My mama told me how that old stuff goes.
Ma mère m'a tout expliqué.
We'll have plenty of time for that when we get married.
On aura tout le temps qu'on veut, une fois mariés.
You wasn't no livelier than me.
Ça te disait pas plus qu'à moi.
Because you ain't good-looking enough. You ain't even got a ducktail.
T'es pas assez mignon. Tu te mets même pas de gomina.
Well, anyway, I'm done late.
D'ailleurs, il se fait tard.
Let's go on home.
Rentrons.
Some anniversary.
Tu parles d'un anniversaire.
If that's the way you feel about it, I'd just as soon break up, Charlene.
Si c'est ce que tu penses, autant se quitter.
I don't wanna spoil no more anniversaries for you.
Je veux pas te gâcher d'autres anniversaires.
That's the way nice girls get treated in this town!
Voilà comment on traite une chic fille.
I might've known you wasn't dependable.
J'aurais dû m'en douter.
You wasn't even in the backfield either.
T'es même pas arrière.
This jacket's got a hole in the pocket, but don't ask me to sew it for you.
Y a un trou dans ton blouson, mais je le recoudrai pas.
You can give me back my pictures too.
Rends-moi mes photos.
I don't want you showing all the other boys and telling how hot I am.
Tu raconteras pas comme j'étais sexy en les montrant.
You wasn't very hot.
Pas tant que ça.
I hope you ain't down in the mouth about Charlene.
T'as le cafard pour Charlene ?
- I ain't blue about her. - What are you blue about then?
- C'est pas pour ça. - Pour quoi, alors ?
Ain't nobody to go with in this town.
Y a personne avec qui sortir, ici.
Jacy's the only pretty girl in school and Duane's got her.
Jacy est jolie, mais Duane sort avec.
I'd call that his tough luck.
C'est bien sa veine.
You don't have to eat so fast. You ain't in a race.
Mange pas si vite, y a pas le feu.
Jacy will bring you more misery than she'll ever be worth.
Jacy en fait voir de dures pour rien.
Did your dad give you this?
Ton père t'a donné ça ?
He needs all he's got.
Il peut pas se le permettre.
Wouldn't hurt you to take something from him once in a while.
Ça te ferait pas de mal de te servir chez lui.
I don't know. You and Duane both in a boarding house.
Je sais pas… Mettre toi et Duane en pension.
Him with the mother, and you with the father. Don't seem right.
Lui a sa mère, toi ton père. C'est pas juste.
And your dad's taking too many pills, you know.
Et ton père prend trop de cachets.
But I'm no one to talk.
J'ai rien à dire.
I never did get on with Mama. I still don't.
Je me suis jamais entendue avec ma mère.
Say, I hear Dan's going back to work soon.
Paraît que Dan reprend le boulot.
- I guess you'll be quitting before long. - Honey…
Tu vas devoir t'en aller.
… we got 4000 dollars' worth of doctor bills to pay.
On doit 4 000 dollars au docteur.
I will probably be making cheeseburgers for your grandkids.
Y a des chances que je serve tes petits-enfants.
… I wonder what my chances are, this morning…
Je me demande quelles sont mes chances
… of interesting you kids in John Keats.
de vous intéresser à John Keats.
None at all.
Aucune.
Joe Bob?
Joe Bob ?
I read that poem of his about the nightingale.
J'ai lu sa poésie sur le rossignol.
I didn't think it was so good.
J'ai pas trouvé ça super.
Sounded like he wanted to be a nightingale.
Comme s'il voulait être un rossignol.
I don't think he wanted to be a nightingale, Joe Bob.
Je ne crois pas qu'il voulait être
Maybe he just wanted to be immortal.
Peut-être voulait-il être immortel.
All you have to do to be immortal is lead a good Christian life.
Pour ça, il suffit de vivre en bon chrétien.
Anyone can do it if they love the Lord.
On peut tous y arriver grâce à Dieu.
Well, maybe so, Joe Bob, maybe so.
Peut-être, Joe Bob.
Here now, let me— Let me read you this.
Écoutez ce que je vais lire :
"When old age shall this generation waste…
"Quand la vieillesse consumera cette génération,
… thou shalt remain in midst of other woe than ours…
tu seras là parmi d'autres douleurs que les nôtres,
… a friend to man, to whom thou say'st:
une amie pour l'homme, à qui tu dis :
'Beauty is truth, truth beauty'—
"La beauté est vérité et vérité, beauté"…
That is all ye know on earth…
Ce que vous savez sur Terre,
… and all ye need to know."
c'est tout ce qu'il faut savoir."
Run, you little pissants, run!
Courez, bande de tocards !
Tough it out! Tough it out! You gotta be men like the rest of us.
Mettez le paquet ! Soyez des hommes.
Ain't none of you pretty enough to be women.
Vous feriez pas de jolies filles.
Quit flapping your arms. You look like a goddamn goose.
Balance pas tes bras comme une oie !
Even for a preacher's boy, you ought to be in better shape.
Même un fils de pasteur doit être en forme.
What kind of female are you ever gonna get?
Quelle femme voudrait de toi ?
Tough it out! Tough it out!
Mettez le paquet !
Run, you little pissants.
Courez, bande de tocards !
All right, off the court.
Bon, ça suffit.
If you all didn't jack off so damn much, maybe you could stay in shape.
Si vous vous branliez moins, ça irait mieux.
Come here a minute, Sonny.
Approche, Sonny.
Now, you do me a favour, and I'll do you one.
J'ai un marché pour toi, donnant, donnant.
Sure, coach.
D'accord.
My old lady's got to go to the doctor tomorrow.
Demain, ma femme va chez le toubib.
You know women. Always something wrong.
Les femmes, ça va jamais !
Yeah, I guess.
Sans doute.
Now, if you'll do this for me, I'll get you out of civics class.
Si tu fais ça, tu seras dispensé d'instruction civique.
I'll be glad to. That's the best offer I've had all day.
Super. La meilleure affaire de la journée.
You tell her you got to get back for practice…
Dis-lui que tu dois t'entraîner
… so she won't stay in there too long.
pour qu'elle abrège.
I've got enough bills to pay already.
J'ai assez de factures à payer.
"Know what the trouble is with you?
"Votre problème,
You ain't got no school spirit."
c'est que vous vous fichez de l'école."
Anarene High School, we love you
Lycée d'Anarene, nous t'aimons
Love you ever so grand
Nous t'aimons par-dessus tout
We will always be so loyal
Nous serons toujours loyaux
Loyal to a man
Loyaux en tout
Anarene, defeat or victory
Anarene, défaite ou victoire
We will always be true
Ce sera toujours avec passion
Anarene High School, we love you
Lycée d'Anarene, nous t'aimons
And we'll fight for you
Et pour toi, nous lutterons
You need a haircut.
Fais-toi couper les cheveux.
Hey, come on, Jimmie Sue. We're hungry over here too.
Jimmie Sue, on a faim ici aussi.
I'm coming. I'm coming. Hold your horses!
J'arrive. Piaffez pas comme ça !
Better watch it. Here comes your mama.
Gare, voilà ta mère.
Jacy, we're having supper at home tonight.
Jacy, nous dînons à la maison.
I expect you there in 15 minutes, you hear?
Rentre dans un quart d'heure.
Okay, Mama. I was just giving the boys a ride.
D'accord, maman. J'accompagnais les garçons.
Now here's a tune that's been on the pop hit list for some weeks.
Voici un air au hit-parade depuis quelques semaines.
Listen and tell us the name.
Il s'intitule ?
What is it?
Qu'est-ce que c'est ?
- "Shrimp Boats." - "Shrimp Boats" You got it!
- "Pêcheurs du Golfe". - Exact !
Very good, Thomas. You were in on that too.
Bravo, Thomas.
All right. There's $120. We're going along fine.
120 dollars. Tout se passe bien.
Now we come to City Limits. This is….
Passons aux villes…
Guess you hate me tonight, huh?
Tu me détestes, hein ?
Oh, Mama, I love you, but I love Duane too. Even if you don't like it.
Je t'aime, et j'aime Duane. Même si ça te déplaît.
I don't care. I'd just hate to see you marry him, that's all.
Je serais navrée que tu l'épouses.
You wouldn't be rich anymore.
Tu n'aurais plus un sou.
- I don't care about money. Not at all. - In two months, he'll stop flattering you.
Je m'en moque.
You're pretty stupid then.
Tu es vraiment bête.
You married Daddy when he was poor, and he got rich, didn't he?
Papa était pauvre. Il s'est enrichi.
Scared your daddy into getting rich, beautiful.
Il a fallu que je lui fasse peur.
If Daddy could do it, Duane could too.
Duane peut y arriver aussi.
Not married to you. You're not scary enough.
Pas avec toi. Tu ne sais pas faire peur.
Well, you're rich and miserable. I sure don't wanna be like you.
Riche et malheureuse. Je ne veux pas être comme toi.
Not much danger of that.
Il n'y a pas de danger.
- You slept with him? - Mama!
- Tu as couché avec lui ? - Maman !
Go to the doctor sometime and arrange something…
Va voir le médecin et arrange-toi
… so you don't have to worry about babies. You have to be careful.
pour ne pas te retrouver enceinte.
But it's a sin unless you're married. You know I wouldn't do that.
C'est un péché sans être mariée. Je ne ferai jamais ça.
Don't be so mealy-mouthed!
Ne fais pas ta sainte nitouche !
I thought if you slept with him…
Si tu couchais avec lui,
… you might find out that there isn't anything magic about him.
tu découvrirais qu'il n'a rien de magique.
Then we can send you away to a good school—
Tu irais dans une bonne école…
- But I don't wanna leave. - Marry some wealthy boy.
Je ne veux pas partir.
Why can't I stay here and go to college in Wichita Falls?
Pourquoi n'irais-je pas à la fac de Wichita Falls ?
Because.
Parce que.
Everything is flat and empty here.
C'est tellement banal et creux, ici.
And nothing to do!
Il n'y a rien à faire !
Can I have some of that?
Je peux ?
Help yourself. Don't you have any?
Sers-toi. Tu n'en as pas ?
Well, yeah, but I feel like smelling good right now.
Si, mais j'ai envie de sentir bon maintenant.
Don't you ever feel like doing anything right now?
Tu n'as jamais d'envies subites ?
You ought to leave your face just like that.
Pas besoin de te maquiller.
All you really need now is a little eyebrow pencil.
Souligne seulement les sourcils.
Okay. Good night.
Bon. Bonne nuit.
Just remember, beautiful, everything gets old if you do it often enough.
Souviens-toi que tout devient barbant quand on le fait souvent.
So if you wanna find out about monotony real quick, marry Duane.
Si tu veux découvrir la monotonie, épouse Duane.
Hello.
Allô ?
- Abilene, you asleep? - No.
- Abilene, tu dors ? - Non.
Feel like company?
Envie de compagnie ?
Well, I thought I'd drive out, see how my well is coming.
Je pensais faire un saut au puits.
Drill hard. You're better at oil wells anyway.
Fore bien. Tu t'y connais mieux en puits de pétrole.
Hello, Sonny. What you want?
Que veux-tu, Sonny ?
Coach said you need a driver.
L'entraîneur m'a dit de vous emmener.
Didn't he tell you I was coming?
Il vous a rien dit ?
No, he didn't mention it. I thought he was gonna drive me himself.
Non, je pensais que c'était lui qui m'accompagnerait.
I guess he just couldn't get off.
Il n'a pas dû pouvoir se libérer.
Let me just get the radio.
J'éteins la radio.
Is it something bad?
C'est grave ?
No.
Non.
It's something very….
C'est quelque chose de très…
Thank you.
Merci.
Here's the keys.
Les clés.
I guess I'd better be getting back to school.
Il faut que je retourne à l'école.
It was nice of you to drive me.
Merci de m'avoir accompagnée.
Well, it beats sitting through civics, ma'am.
J'ai pu sécher l'instruction civique.
Wouldn't you like to come in and have a soda?
Tu veux entrer boire un soda ?
If you can stand me for a few more minutes.
Si tu peux me supporter encore un peu.
I hate these northers.
Je déteste ce vent.
Would you prefer milk? Just sit at the table.
Tu préfères du lait ? Assieds-toi.
Or you can go right now if you want.
Ou pars, si tu veux.
I was just scared to be alone for a minute. I'm sorry I made you come in.
J'avais peur de rester seule. Excuse-moi.
I'll take a Dr Pepper.
Je prendrai un soda.
You'll never forgive me, I know.
Tu ne me le pardonneras jamais.
Go on. You don't have to stay any longer.
Va, ne te sens pas obligé de rester.
Thank you for the Dr Pepper.
Merci pour le soda.
I guess you'll be glad when basketball season's over.
Vous serez contente à la fin des tournois.
Why?
Pourquoi ?
Well, coach probably don't get to stay home much…
L'entraîneur doit pas rentrer souvent
… during football and basketball season.
pendant la saison des tournois.
My God, you don't know a thing about it, do you?
Alors, tu ne sais rien, pas vrai ?
You better go on to basketball practice.
Retourne à ton entraînement.
Thanks for the Dr Pepper.
Merci pour le soda.
- Hi, Jacy. - Oh, hi.
Salut, Jacy.
Duane coming?
Duane va venir ?
Say, you know Bobby Sheen, don't you? Over at Wichita Falls?
- Tu connais Bobby Sheen ? - Je l'ai rencontré au country club.
Well, he's gonna have this midnight swimming party tonight.
Il y a une fête à la piscine chez lui, ce soir.
- You wanna run over there with me? - I can't.
- Tu m'y accompagnes ? - Je peux pas.
I guess you heard about the last one.
On t'a raconté la dernière.
His folks were gone to Miami, and everybody swam naked.
Ses vieux étaient à Miami. On a nagé à poil.
His folks are gone again, so it'll probably be pretty wild.
Là, ses vieux sont repartis, ça va chauffer.
Sure wish you could come. Bobby has great parties.
J'aimerais que tu viennes. C'est super, chez Bobby.
A lot of kids from the club gonna be there.
Il y aura plein de jeunes du club.
Gee, Lester, I'd like to go.
J'aimerais bien y aller.
I'm gonna have a big problem with Duane though.
Avec Duane, ce sera dur.
Well, don't go off without me. Maybe I can.
Pars pas sans moi. Je pourrai peut-être.
- Hi, Duane. - What did Lester want?
Salut.
Oh, Lester. He's such a bore.
Oh, ce qu'il est rasoir…
- Hey, Abilene! - What do you say, buddy?
- Salut, Abilene ! - Ça boume ?
Hey there. Hi.
Bonsoir.
Merry Christmas.
Joyeux Noël !
This is Jackie Lee French. This is Lois Farrow, my boss's wife.
Jackie Lee French. Lois Farrow, la femme du patron.
What do you mean, kissing her like that?
Et tu l'embrasses comme ça ?
I ought to slap your face!
Je devrais vous gifler !
Well, why don't you just kiss my ass?
Et mon cul, vous l'embrassez ?
I never come here to referee no fight.
Je veux pas arbitrer une bagarre.
Well, good, then come dance with me.
Viens, danse avec moi.
Get yourself a drink, honey. I'll be back.
Sers-toi à boire, je reviens.
Hi, Ruth.
Bonsoir, Ruth.
Wait for me outside.
Attends-moi dehors.
It's too hot in here. Let's go outside.
Ce qu'il fait chaud. Sortons.
I don't want drunks tromping on my feet.
Et on va me marcher sur les pieds.
I got something to give you anyway.
Moi, j'ai quelque chose pour toi.
Hi, Sonny.
Salut, Sonny.
Hi, Dad.
Salut, papa.
How you doing?
Comment va ?
Okay.
Bien.
Well, that's good.
C'est chouette.
See you.
À bientôt.
Sure.
Ouais.
- You mean, my Christmas present. - Yep.
Mon cadeau de Noël ?
I haven't had time to get you anything yet.
J'ai pas eu le temps de t'en faire un.
I haven't had a minute to shop.
J'ai pas eu une minute.
Hope you like it. I saved up for six months to get it.
Ça fait six mois que j'économise.
Oh, it's just beautiful.
Elle est superbe.
It's just what I've been wanting.
Juste ce que je voulais.
You're so sweet, spending all that money on me.
Dépenser tout ça pour moi !
Oh, you're so sexy, Duane.
Que tu es sexy, Duane.
I just wish I didn't have to leave you tonight.
Dommage que je doive partir, ce soir.
Well, you don't.
Reste !
Oh, I do too. I could just kill my mother!
J'aimerais. Ma mère est à tuer !
She made me promise to go to a swim party in Wichita with Lester Marlow.
Elle m'a fait promettre d'aller à une fête avec Lester Marlow.
Because his folks are rich. Don't be mad.
Il est riche. Te mets pas en colère.
I ain't mad at you, but goddamn it!
Non, mais merde !
It's all Lester's fault. He keeps asking Mama.
Lester a tanné maman avec ça.
All I wanna do is stay with the man I love.
Alors que je veux rester avec celui que j'aime.
No, no, Duane! I gotta go. I gotta go.
Non, je dois m'en aller !
What do you mean, asking my girl for a date?
Comme ça, on invite ma copine ?
- You turn me loose! - I will when you're ready to fight.
- Lâche-moi ! - Quand tu seras prêt à te battre.
Let's have it out!
Réglons ça !
Here, knock off that shit, boys. This is the Christmas season.
Arrêtez vos conneries. C'est Noël.
Run along here, Wichita.
File, Wichita.
I can't stand here all night protecting your shoeshine.
Je passerai pas la nuit à protéger tes belles pompes.
I just don't know what I'm gonna do about him. He's so crazy about me.
Je ne sais plus quoi faire. Il est fou de moi.
Nothing against Duane, but that's a roughneck for you.
J'ai rien contre lui, mais c'est un péquenot.
They aren't sophisticated about these things.
Il fait pas dans la dentelle.
Well, Merry Christmas!
Joyeux Noël !
Come on in, let's have some punch, boy.
Allons prendre un verre de punch.
- Hi, Sonny. - Oh, hi.
Bonjour, Sonny.
- Wanna help me? - Okay.
Tu viens m'aider ?
You're not dancing. Don't you have a girlfriend?
Tu ne danses pas. Pas d'amie ?
I did have. We broke up a couple months ago.
Pas depuis quelques mois.
Oh, why? Mind my asking?
Pourquoi ?
I was going with Charlene Duggs.
Je sortais avec Charlene Duggs.
She thought I got fresh with her. I never did, really.
J'allais trop loin, pour elle. C'est pas vrai.
I guess we broke up because we didn't like each other much to begin with.
Ça a cassé parce qu'on s'aimait pas beaucoup.
I hope you're not sad about it.
Tu n'es pas triste, j'espère.
I don't think Charlene's near nice enough for you.
Charlene n'est pas assez bien pour toi.
I didn't see you dancing.
Vous avez pas dansé.
No, I don't dance much.
Je ne danse pas souvent.
Will you drive me to the clinic again next week?
Tu m'accompagnes chez le médecin, la semaine prochaine ?
Well, you bet.
Garanti.
We better not dawdle here.
Ne traînons pas ici.
Bobby.
Bobby.
Hey, look! New victims!
De nouvelles victimes !
Glad you could make it. We're dressed informally.
Content de te voir. Petite tenue de rigueur.
You know Annie-Annie.
Annie-Annie.
Wanna join the club?
Tu entres dans la bande ?
Sure.
Oui.
Well, you gotta get undressed out there on the diving board.
Tu dois te déshabiller sur le plongeoir.
So everybody gets to watch.
Pour qu'on regarde tous.
We all do it the first time.
On y est tous passés.
- That's the rule. - Yeah. I did it last Easter.
- C'est la règle. - Je l'ai fait à Pâques.
Everybody out for the strip show!
Sortez tous, strip-tease !
Don't pay any attention to Sandy. He's my little brother.
Fais pas attention à mon frère.
If he gooses you or anything, I'll make him go to bed.
S'il te tripote, il ira au lit.
Goodness! I hope I don't fall off this thing.
Pourvu que je tombe pas !
Sandy can fish you out if you do.
Sandy te repêchera.
Duane, been looking for you. Hey, where's Jacy?
Je te cherchais. Où est Jacy ?
Oh, don't remind him. We just got him quiet. Want a drink?
Il venait enfin de se calmer. Tu bois un coup ?
- Where'd you get it? - Found it in a guy's car.
- Où t'as eu ça ? - Dans une bagnole.
- When he weren't looking. - Let's do something.
- Il regardait pas. - Bougeons !
Good idea. Why don't we hunt up some pussy?
On cherche un trou à baiser ?
Oh, you wouldn't know what to do with it if we found some.
Tu saurais pas quoi faire, si on en trouvait.
What happened?
Qu'y a-t-il ?
Lester took his girl to a swimming party.
Lester a emmené sa copine à une fête.
Let's all go out and get a fuck.
Allons tirer un coup.
I know where's a heifer. It belongs to my Uncle Hank.
Je sais où y a une génisse. Celle de mon oncle.
Why the hell not?
Pourquoi pas ?
- I say a heifer beats nothing. - Pussy's pussy!
- Une génisse, y a pas mieux. - C'est un trou.
I don't want no heifer.
Très peu pour moi.
We ought to buy Billy a piece of ass.
Billy veut une gonzesse.
- Yeah, we oughtn't let him die a virgin. - Yeah.
Faut pas le laisser crever puceau.
Mama says idiot kids don't live long.
Les idiots, ça meurt jeune.
He ain't no idiot kid. He just don't talk.
Il est pas idiot, il parle pas.
Bet he's still a virgin, though.
Mais c'est un puceau.
Hey, we ought to fix him up with Jimmie Sue.
Arrangeons le coup avec Jimmie Sue.
It'd make no difference to Billy.
- Il fera pas la différence. - On devrait pas faire ça.
Why not? It wouldn't cost us more than $1.50.
Ça coûtera 1,50 $, pas plus.
If that's all, we ought to get her ourselves.
Dans ce cas, profitons-en aussi.
Shit! A heifer's better than Jimmie Sue.
Je préfère encore une génisse.
Get the stupid little thing in here. I ain't got all night.
Faites-le entrer, j'ai pas toute la nuit.
Let's get those pants off, boys.
Enlevez-lui ses pantalons !
You won't be a virgin much longer.
- Tu seras plus puceau longtemps. - Tu vas baiser.
Grab on now. Come on, do your job.
Allez, fais ta petite affaire.
Get her, Billy-boy!
Vas-y, Billy !
This is the dumbest thing I ever seen!
C'est ridicule !
- He don't even know what to do! - Come on, Billy. It worked for me.
Il sait même pas quoi faire !
Damn it, put it to her, boy!
Mets-la-lui !
- Get her, Billy. - Come on, Billy. Screw it to her, boy.
- Prends-la. - Défonce-la, Billy.
You stop that yelling out there.
Arrêtez de brailler.
It ain't even in!
Il est même pas dedans !
Goddamn!
Merde !
Goddamn, you stupid little thing!
Merde, espèce d'idiot !
Couldn't even wait. Look at this mess!
Il a pas attendu. Quel chantier !
You okay, Billy?
Ça va, Billy ?
You all right?
Tu vas bien ?
Well, now I know. Idiots as bad as Mexicans.
Les idiots valent pas mieux que les Mexicains.
Don't bother me no more for that crazy thing.
Venez plus me chercher pour ça.
Wouldn't mess with him again for less than three and a half.
Je le referai pas avec lui à moins de 3,50 $.
Which one of you bloodied his nose?
Qui l'a fait saigner du nez ?
I've told you all not to fight with Billy. He don't understand about fighting.
Vous battez pas avec lui, ça veut rien dire pour lui.
What happened, Sonny?
Que s'est-il passé ?
- It weren't none of us, Sam. - No, it was Jimmie Sue.
- C'est pas nous, Sam. - C'est Jimmie Sue.
Jimmie Sue? How'd he get messed up with her?
Jimmie Sue ? Comment ça se fait ?
We bought him a piece of ass. Thought he was tired of being a virgin.
On la lui a payée. Pour qu'elle le dépucelle.
She got mad about something and bloodied his nose.
Elle s'est mise en colère et l'a frappé.
You boys get on out of here.
Tirez-vous, les gars.
I don't wanna have no more to do with you.
Et je veux plus vous voir.
Scaring a poor, unfortunate creature like Billy…
Effrayer un pauvre malheureux
… just so you could have a few laughs.
rien que pour rire !
I've been around that trashy behaviour all my life.
J'ai passé ma vie à voir ces saloperies.
I'm getting tired of putting up with it.
J'en ai assez de laisser courir.
You can stay out of this pool hall, my café…
Disparaissez de mon billard,
… and my picture show too.
de mon café et de mon cinéma.
I don't want no more of your business.
Je veux plus avoir affaire à vous.
We didn't mean for anything bad to happen, Sam. We—
On voulait pas que ça finisse comme ça.
You didn't even have the decency to wash his face.
Vous lui avez même pas lavé la figure.
We're his best customers. He can't run us off.
On est ses meilleurs clients. Il peut pas nous virer.
Can he?
Il peut ?
Lucky I fell asleep. I'd hate not being able to shoot no pool.
Heureusement que je dormais. Ce serait dur sans billard.
You sure he won't come?
Il arrivera pas, sûr ?
You know he won't. He's just starting basketball practice.
Mais non, il doit entraîner l'équipe de basket.
It's all right.
Ça va.
I'm sorry I cried.
Excuse-moi d'avoir pleuré.
Just scared, I guess.
La peur, je crois.
He ain't gonna come.
Il arrivera pas.
They're probably running plays right now, I bet.
Ils doivent être en train de jouer.
No, not scared of that.
Non, pas peur de ça.
Scared I could never do this, I guess.
Mais de pas y arriver.
Can't seem to do anything without crying about it.
Je peux rien faire sans me mettre à pleurer.
How could you like me?
Comment pourrais-tu bien m'aimer ?
I like you.
Je t'aime bien.
I'm glad.
Ça me fait plaisir.
Come on in. I ain't gonna throw bottles at you.
Entre, je vais pas te mordre.
What have you been doing? You lost weight.
Tu en es où ? Tu as maigri.
Ain't had any of your cheeseburgers in weeks.
Tes cheeseburgers m'ont manqué.
Come on. I'll fix you one.
Je vais t'en préparer un.
Even though that wasn't a very nice thing y'all done to Billy.
C'est pas bien, ce que vous avez fait à Billy.
Can't blame Sam.
Je comprends Sam.
- Was that your idea? - No.
C'était ton idée ?
Duane's? He was there, wasn't he?
De Duane ? Il était là, hein ?
Just didn't have the decency to own up to it.
Il a même pas eu l'honnêteté de le dire.
Don't worry, I won't tell on him. I should, though.
Je le dirai pas, va. Je devrais !
Sure smells good.
Ça sent bon.
One thing I know for sure.
Une chose est sûre.
A person can't sneeze in this town…
Ici, si t'éternues, on t'offre un mouchoir.
- What you mean? - Nothing.
- Que veux-tu dire ? - Rien.
It's an awful small town for any kind of carrying on.
C'est une petite ville, tout se sait.
Don't forget to put some onions on.
Oublie pas les oignons.
And some people got a lot of guns.
Et y en a qui ont des flingues.
All right, you don't need my advice anyway.
T'as pas besoin de mes conseils.
Why don't you go play a record? These will be done in a minute.
Mets un disque. Ce sera bientôt prêt.
Just come in to say hello to Genevieve.
Je suis passé dire bonjour à Geneviève.
… food's getting cold.
Ça va refroidir.
What are you grinning about?
C'est quoi, ce sourire ?
Chicken-fry me a steak, and try to use meat this time.
Fais-moi un steak. Avec de la vraie viande.
I heard about the ball game last night.
On m'a dit, pour le match d'hier.
121 to 14.
121 à 14.
Must be pretty near a record.
Presque un record.
I'm sorry.
Je suis désolé.
I reckon y'all need glasses.
Vous devriez porter des lunettes.
Now hold still.
Ne bouge pas.
Want some more cookies?
Encore des biscuits ?
- More milk? - I'm full.
- Du lait ? - Je peux rien avaler.
How come you've stayed with the coach?
Pourquoi tu restes avec l'entraîneur ?
You don't like him much.
Tu l'aimes pas beaucoup.
I wasn't brought up to leave a husband.
On m'a pas élevée pour quitter mon mari.
I guess that's why.
Ça doit être pour ça.
Maybe I was just scared to.
Peut-être que j'avais peur aussi.
I never noticed how ugly this room is.
J'avais jamais remarqué que c'était si moche, ici.
What's your favourite colour?
Ta couleur préférée ?
I don't know. Blue.
Je sais pas. Bleu.
- Maybe I'll re-paper it. - Why'd you marry him?
- Je changerai le papier. - Pourquoi tu l'as épousé ?
I don't know.
Je sais pas.
My mother didn't like him. Maybe that was it.
Ma mère l'aimait pas. C'est peut-être pour ça.
But I was 20 years old.
J'avais 20 ans.
I thought hairy-chested football coaches were about it.
Je croyais qu'il y avait pas mieux qu'un entraîneur poilu.
I'm gonna buy us a new quilt.
J'achèterai un dessus-de-lit.
A blue one.
Un bleu.
What you think he'd do if he found us?
Il ferait quoi, s'il nous surprenait ?
Shoot us, probably.
Il nous descendrait.
He's always glad to have an excuse to use his deer rifle.
Il sort son fusil pour un oui ou pour un non.
I thought you boys wanted to fish.
Je croyais que vous vouliez pêcher. Surveillez les bouchons.
I don't think there's anything in this tank except turtles.
Y a que des tortues, là-dedans.
That's what I like about it, tell you the truth.
Honnêtement, c'est ce qui me plaît.
- Wanna try one? - Sure.
- T'en veux une ? - Ouais.
I never liked to clean fish or eat them either.
Je déteste nettoyer et manger le poisson.
You spend half your time picking out bone.
On passe son temps à retirer les arêtes.
I just come out here to get a little scenery.
Je suis venu pour le paysage.
Too pretty a day to spend in town.
Faisait trop beau pour rester en ville.
You wouldn't believe how this country's changed.
T'as pas idée de ce que ce pays a changé.
First time I seen it, there wasn't a mesquite tree on it.
Quand je suis arrivé, y avait pas un arbuste.
Or a prickly pear neither.
Ni même un figuier de Barbarie.
I used to own this land, you know.
Cette terre m'a appartenu.
First time I watered a horse at this tank…
La 1re fois que j'ai abreuvé un cheval ici,
… was more than 40 years ago.
c'était il y a plus de 40 ans.
I reckon the reason I always drag you out here is…
Je crois que je vous ai amenés ici
… I'm just as sentimental as the next feller when it comes to old times.
parce que je deviens sentimental en parlant du bon vieux temps.
Old times.
Le bon vieux temps.
I brought a young lady swimming out here once…
J'ai amené une fille nager ici,
… more than 20 years ago.
y a plus de vingt ans.
It was after my wife had lost her mind.
Après que ma femme a perdu la tête.
And my boys was dead.
Et la mort de mes fils.
Me and this young lady was pretty wild, I guess.
Elle et moi, on était déchaînés.
In pretty deep.
Et drôlement amoureux.
We used to come here on horseback and swim without no bathing suits.
On venait à cheval et on se baignait tout nus.
One day, she wanted to swim the horses across this tank.
Un jour, elle a voulu traverser l'étang à cheval.
Kind of a crazy thing to do, but we done it anyway.
C'était de la folie, mais on l'a fait.
She bet me a silver dollar she could beat me across.
On a parié un dollar d'argent qu'elle me battrait.
She did.
Elle a gagné.
This old horse I was riding didn't wanna take the water.
Mon canasson voulait pas entrer dans l'eau.
But she was always looking for something to do like that.
Elle était toujours à inventer des trucs comme ça.
Something wild.
Des trucs dingues.
I'll bet she's still got that silver dollar.
Je parie qu'elle a encore ce dollar.
Whatever happened to her?
Qu'est-ce qu'elle est devenue ?
Oh, she growed up.
Elle a grandi.
She was just a girl then, really.
C'était encore une gamine.
Here, let me help you with that.
Je vais t'aider.
Why didn't you ever marry her after your wife died?
Pourquoi tu l'as pas épousée à la fin ?
She was already married.
Elle était déjà mariée.
Her and her husband was young and miserable with one another…
Elle et son mari étaient malheureux,
… like so many young married folks are.
comme beaucoup de jeunes mariés.
I thought they'd change with some age…
Je pensais que ça changerait avec l'âge,
… but it didn't turn out that way.
mais non.
- Is being married always so miserable? - No. Not really.
- C'est si triste, le mariage ? - Non.
About 80 percent of the time, I guess.
Seulement huit fois sur dix.
We ought to go to a real fishing tank next year.
On ira à un étang poissonneux l'an prochain.
It don't do to think about things like that too much.
C'est pas bon de penser à des trucs comme ça.
If she was here, I'd probably be just as crazy now…
Si elle était là, je serais aussi fou d'elle
… as I was then in about five minutes.
qu'avant, en moins de cinq minutes.
Ain't that ridiculous?
C'est idiot, non ?
No, it ain't really.
Non, ça l'est pas.
Being crazy about a woman like her is always the right thing to do.
Être fou d'une femme pareille, c'est la meilleure chose à faire.
Being a decrepit, old bag of bones, that's what's ridiculous.
Être un vieux sac d'os, c'est ça, qui est idiot.
Getting old.
Vieillir.
My God, I'm glad I wasn't on fire.
Heureusement qu'y a pas le feu.
I would've burned to death before you got one button undone.
J'aurais été carbonisée avant que tu défasses ce bouton.
I'm going to get a drink of water.
Je vais boire un verre d'eau.
I wondered where you went. Annie-Annie asleep?
Je me demandais où tu étais. Annie-Annie dort ?
Nice. You a virgin?
Pas mal. Tu es vierge ?
Guess I am.
Oui.
Too bad.
Dommage.
- I don't wanna be, though. - I don't blame you.
- Je veux plus l'être. - Je te comprends.
Come see me when you're not.
Reviens quand tu le seras plus.
Why don't we just go someplace? I'm sick and tired of this town.
Si on se tirait ? J'en ai marre de ce patelin.
- You're the only friend I got. - You mean, go and stay gone?
- T'es mon seul copain. - Pour toujours ?
No, I don't know.
Non, je sais pas.
Hey, we go to Mexico. Be back sometime Monday.
Allons au Mexique. On revient lundi.
- You reckon the pickup would make it? - Yeah. How much money you got?
- Le camion tiendrait ? - Oui, t'as combien de fric ?
Oh, 30 bucks about.
30 dollars.
Well, I got 40. We can make it. Come on!
Moi, 40. C'est bon ! Viens !
You boys want—? Hey.
Vous…
- Where are you going? - Mexico.
- Où allez-vous ? - Au Mexique.
Where?
Où ça ?
Better come with us, Sam. We're headed for the valley.
Viens avec nous. On va dans la vallée.
- Going where did you say? - Mexico.
- Où ça ? - Au Mexique.
- It's about the wildest. - All the way down.
- L'aventure ! - Tout droit !
You going all the way to Mexico tonight in this old heap of junk?
Vous allez au Mexique ce soir avec ce tacot pourri ?
Reckon the town will get along without us till Monday?
La ville tiendra le coup sans nous jusqu'à lundi ?
I reckon.
Je pense.
If I was young enough to bounce, I'd probably go with you.
Si j'étais jeune, je viendrais avec vous.
- Need any money? - No, we got plenty.
- Besoin d'argent ? - On en a.
Well, you'd better take some for some insurance.
Prenez-en un peu plus, au cas où.
Take money below that border, it sort of melts sometimes.
Passé la frontière, l'argent fond.
Thanks, Sam.
Merci, Sam.
Try not to drink too much of that buggy water.
Buvez pas la flotte du pays.
We'll just drink beer and tequila.
Non, bière et tequila seulement.
You catch the clap, you'll wish you hadn't drunk nothing.
Si vous chopez la chtouille, vous regretterez d'en avoir bu.
Oh, well.
Bon.
We'll see you.
À bientôt.
So long!
Salut !
We're back.
On est rentrés.
My stomach don't feel so good. Got any more of those Tums?
Je me sens pas très bien. T'as des cachets ?
You ate them all before we got to San Antone.
Tu les as tous bouffés avant San Antonio.
Genevieve will have something. My stomach don't feel so good.
Geneviève a ce qu'il faut. Je me sens pas bien.
"Closed."
Fermé.
Closed?
Fermé ?
I ain't never seen her closed before.
Je l'avais jamais vu fermé.
No, not even for Christmas.
Pas même à Noël.
Maybe Sam will have something. I'm sick.
Sam aura quelque chose. J'ai mal au cœur.
Well, it ain't that early.
Il est pas si tôt que ça.
Must be some kind of holiday.
Ça doit être un jour férié.
Sam don't close on holidays.
Sam ferme jamais.
Maybe he had to go someplace.
Il a dû aller quelque part.
Well, let's go ask Andy.
Demandons à Andy.
Asleep. Everybody that's got any sense.
Les gens sensés sont au lit.
Why'd Sam close the café?
Pourquoi Sam a fermé ?
Oh, yeah. Y'all been gone, ain't you?
Vous étiez partis, hein ?
Gone to Mexico.
Au Mexique.
- You don't know about it. - About what?
- Vous savez pas. - Quoi ?
Sam died yesterday morning.
Sam est mort hier matin.
Died?
Mort ?
Yep. Quite a blow.
Tout d'un coup.
Keeled over one of the snooker tables. Had a stroke.
Il est tombé sur une table de billard. Une attaque.
- Sam the Lion? - Yep.
Sam le Lion ?
Sam's dead.
Sam est mort.
He was quite a feller.
Un sacré bonhomme.
He had his own way of doing things, that's for sure.
Ça, il en faisait qu'à sa tête.
They found his will. Craziest thing you ever heard.
On a trouvé son testament. Délirant !
He left you the pool hall, Sonny. What do you think about that?
Il t'a laissé le billard, Sonny. Qu'est-ce que tu dis de ça ?
He left Genevieve the café.
Geneviève a le café.
That's the only thing he done that made any sense.
C'est le seul legs qui ait du sens.
Left the picture show to old Miss Mosey.
Mlle Mosey garde le cinéma.
Hell, she's too far gone to even run a popcorn machine.
Elle est même plus fichue de faire du pop-corn.
And the craziest thing of all…
Mais le plus fort,
… he left $1000 to Joe Bob Blanton, the preacher's boy.
c'est qu'il donne 1 000 $ à Joe Bob, le fils du pasteur.
Beats all I ever heard of.
Ça, ça m'a soufflé.
He could just as easily left that to me.
Il aurait mieux fait de me les filer.
I deserve it at least as much as that ignorant little bastard.
Je les mérite autant que ce petit merdeux.
Anyhow, it's done.
Bah, c'est fait.
They're burying him tomorrow.
On l'enterre demain.
Come in.
Entre.
- I love you. - I love you too.
- Je t'aime. - Moi aussi.
Oh, Duane, hurry.
Dépêche-toi.
What's wrong, honey?
Qu'est-ce qu'il y a ?
I don't know.
Je sais pas.
That tickles. You know I can't stand to be tickled.
Ça chatouille. Tu sais que j'aime pas ça.
What's the matter? Aren't you gonna do it?
Quoi, tu le fais pas ?
I don't know what's wrong.
Je sais pas ce qui cloche.
How could anything be wrong? Just go on and do it.
Ce qui cloche ? Vas-y, c'est tout.
Oh, what's the matter with you?
Qu'est-ce qui te prend ?
I don't know. Something's happened.
Je sais pas, y a quelque chose.
Well, get off a minute! You might fall and mash me.
Pousse-toi ! Tu vas m'écraser.
I don't know what happened.
Je ne comprends pas.
It was Mexico. No telling what you got down there.
Le Mexique ! Que t'ont-elles fait ?
I just hate you! I don't know why I ever went with you.
Je te déteste ! Comment j'ai pu sortir avec toi ?
I don't know what happened.
Je comprends pas.
Put your clothes on. You think I wanna sit around here and look at you naked?
Rhabille-toi, tu crois que je veux te voir tout nu ?
I knew you couldn't do it. Now I'll never not be a virgin!
Je le savais. Je vais rester vierge.
What do we tell everybody? The whole class knows.
Que va-t-on dire ? Toute la classe le sait.
I just wanna cry. You're the meanest boy I ever saw.
J'en pleurerais. Tu es minable.
My mother was dead-right about you.
Ma mère avait raison !
I don't know what happened.
Je ne comprends pas.
Don't go out there! We haven't had time to do it. They'd know.
T'en va pas ! C'était pas assez long.
I don't want one soul to know. You better not tell one soul.
Personne doit savoir. N'en parle pas.
You just pretend it was wonderful!
Dis que c'était super !
Well, I'm sorry. I don't know what happened.
Je ne comprends pas.
If you say that one more time, I'll bite you!
Redis ça et je t'assomme !
Tell us about it, Jacy. What was it like?
Raconte, c'était comment ?
I just can't describe it.
Je sais pas comment dire.
I just can't describe it in words.
Je trouve pas les mots pour le dire.
I can do it now. I know I can.
Je peux maintenant, je le sais.
Oh, quit prissing! I don't think you did it right anyway.
Arrête ton cinéma, je crois pas que t'aies brillé.
Come on.
Viens.
It's your graduation present. Hope you like it.
Un cadeau de fin d'études. Il te plaira, j'espère.
I never seen one as nice.
C'est le plus beau que j'aie vu.
What's on your feeble mind, Duane?
Que veux-tu, petite tête ?
Same as it's been. I want a date.
Un rendez-vous.
Why don't you just go back to Mexico?
Retourne donc au Mexique.
I guess girls are just easier to please down there.
Les filles doivent y être plus faciles.
Just go with me one more time.
Sors avec moi encore une fois.
You can at least see me.
Au moins pour me voir.
Find somebody else to pester. Got a new boyfriend.
Va embêter une autre. J'ai un copain.
- And I can't be talking to you. - Who?
- Je peux plus te parler. - Qui ?
- Bobby Sheen, of course. - Bobby Sheen?
Bobby Sheen.
- You crazy? - I certainly am not.
- T'es folle ? - Pas du tout.
I guess I wanted to go with him all along and never realised it.
Je crois que je l'ai toujours voulu sans le savoir.
Maybe we'll see you in Wichita sometime.
À un de ces jours, à Wichita.
Goddamn it! Goddamn it to hell!
Bordel de merde !
I hate to see you go, Duane.
Je regrette que tu partes.
Not a goddamn thing to stay for.
J'ai rien à faire ici.
Roughnecks say you can get a job out in Odessa anytime.
Paraît qu'il y a du boulot à Odessa.
Come on back if you don't.
Reviens s'il y en a pas.
Hey, listen, you hear they busted up, let me know.
Si ça pète entre eux, dis-le-moi.
Hi. Didn't hear you.
J'ai rien entendu.
Gene home?
Gene est là ?
No, he and Mama went to the club.
Non, il est au club avec maman.
What are you doing home on a Saturday night?
À la maison, un samedi soir ?
Bobby Sheen ran off and got married.
Bobbie Sheen s'est marié.
Annie-Annie Martin.
Avec Annie-Annie Martin.
Want me to turn the TV off?
J'éteins la télé ?
No, I'm gonna go play some pool. Tell your dad that well came in okay.
Je vais faire un billard. Dis à ton père que le puits marche.
I wish I could go to the pool hall. I've always wanted to.
J'ai toujours rêvé de jouer au billard.
It's terrible, the things girls aren't allowed to do.
C'est fou, ce que les filles doivent pas faire.
Well, hell, come on. I'll show you the pool hall.
Viens. Je te montrerai.
Aren't there people there?
Il y aura des gens ?
If there are, they'll be in back asleep now.
Ils doivent tous dormir.
Won't bother us. Got my own key.
On nous dérangera pas, j'ai ma clé.
Okay, I will then.
Alors, d'accord.
Goodness, it sure is dark in here.
Ce qu'il fait noir, ici.
What a night! I never thought something like this would happen.
Quelle soirée ! J'aurais jamais pensé que ça arriverait.
How about hopping out?
Descends, tu veux ?
Oh, he's just awful, Mama! Why do you fool with him?
Il est affreux ! Que fais-tu avec lui ?
- Daddy's nicer than him, isn't he? - He sure is, beautiful.
- Papa est bien plus gentil. - Oui.
Your daddy's a very nice man.
Ton père est très gentil.
I ought to been giving Abilene hell instead of him.
C'est à Abilene que je devrais en faire baver.
Bobby was the last one. I'm just gonna be an old maid.
Bobby était le dernier. Je finirai vieille fille.
That's just the way it goes sometimes. You win a few, you lose a few.
C'est comme ça. On gagne, et on perd.
What do you do?
Que faut-il faire ?
Nothing's ever the way it's supposed to be.
Tout va de travers.
You're right. Come on.
Tu as raison. Viens.
I want to tell you, what I've done has not worked out too well.
Ce que j'ai fait n'a pas donné de bons résultats.
I think maybe we better think of something else for you.
On ferait mieux de te trouver autre chose.
Right now, I guess Ruth Popper's got about as good a setup as anyone.
Au fond, Ruth s'est bien débrouillée.
Why, sure. Sonny's reasonably good-looking and he's young.
Oui, Sonny n'est pas trop mal et il est jeune.
Don't you know about that? It's been going on about six months now.
Tu n'es pas au courant ? Ça dure depuis six mois.
- I thought you kids knew everything. - That's silly!
- Les jeunes savent pas ça ? - C'est ridicule.
She's 40 years old.
Elle a 40 ans.
So am I, honey. It's kind of an itchy age.
Moi aussi. C'est l'âge où ça démange.
Want an orange?
Une orange ?
I don't believe it.
C'est pas vrai.
Sonny's always wanted to go with me.
Sonny rêvait de sortir avec moi.
Pretty easy shot, sheriff.
C'est facile, shérif.
Sheriff, we got some trouble.
Shérif, des ennuis !
Goddamn you, Monroe! You made me scratch.
Bon Dieu, tu m'as fait louper mon tir !
Sorry, sheriff, but Johnny Clarg's little girl's kind of been kidnapped.
Désolé, mais la petite des Clarg a été enlevée.
They say the preacher's boy put her in his car two hours ago.
Le fils du pasteur l'a emmenée en voiture.
Well, what the hell? Maybe Joe Bob just give her a ride home.
Ben quoi ? Peut-être qu'il la raccompagne.
Be doing her a favour in this hot weather.
Il lui rend service avec cette chaleur.
Who'd want to kidnap Molly Clarg?
Qui enlèverait Molly Clarg ?
I just know she's not home.
Elle est pas chez elle.
They was seen headed out of town toward Olney.
On les a vus partir vers Olney.
- … gonna molest her or something. - Sonny.
l'agresse ou je ne sais quoi.
You and some of these boys come with us.
Toi et quelques autres, venez.
If that's the way it is, no telling what we'll find.
Si c'est ça, je vous dis pas ce qu'on trouvera.
Molly! Molly!
Molly !
Get him! Ain't you going to?
Arrêtez-le ! Qu'attendez-vous ?
Here's my little girl.
Ma petite fille !
He's the one that done it. Why don't you get him?
C'est lui qui l'a enlevée. Arrêtez-le !
If my husband was here, he'd kill him dead.
Si mon mari était là, il le descendrait.
What did you do to that child? We know you done something.
Que lui as-tu fait ? Tu as fait quelque chose.
Come on.
Allez !
Filthy!
Dégoûtant !
Here now, grab her. None of this goddamn frenzy.
Retenez-la ! Pas de crise d'hystérie ici.
It's the Lord's justice, son.
C'est la justice divine.
You'll suffer with the murderer and the thief.
Tu souffriras avec l'assassin et le voleur.
Sonny, drive that Plymouth to town. We gotta get this man to jail.
Sonny, ramène sa voiture en ville. On le conduit en prison.
- Doctor said he didn't do nothing. - Never had the guts.
- Il a rien fait, dit le toubib. - Il a pas osé.
- Preacher's boy. - Sheriff figured he done something.
- Le fils du pasteur. - Le shérif dit pas ça.
Isn't it terrible, Sonny? Were you there? Did you see anything?
C'est affreux ! Tu as vu quelque chose ?
Oh, weren't nothing to see except Mrs Clarg.
Y avait rien à voir, sauf Mme Clarg.
If she had a gun, she might've killed us all.
Elle nous aurait tous tués.
Joe Bob didn't do nothing.
Joe Bob a rien fait.
He must've done something. It scares me to death.
Il a forcément fait quelque chose. Ça m'effraie.
You just never can tell when something terrible's gonna happen.
On peut pas prévoir ces horreurs.
It's okay. They got him now.
Ils l'ont arrêté.
I called you before.
Je t'ai appelé tout à l'heure.
You did?
Ah, oui ?
I felt lonesome.
Je me sentais seule.
Thought you might wanna drive around awhile.
Je pensais que t'aimerais te balader.
Well, I'm supposed to be someplace.
Je dois aller quelque part.
I'm still a little scared. Please take me riding.
J'ai encore un peu peur. Emmène-moi, s'il te plaît.
You ever hear from Duane?
Des nouvelles de Duane ?
Got a postcard.
J'ai reçu une carte.
I really feel sad about that.
C'est tellement triste, tout ça.
I guess I'll always be a little bit in love with Duane.
Je l'aimerai toujours un peu. Trop de choses nous séparaient.
It wasn't easy being the one to break up.
Ça a été dur de décider de rompre.
Not here.
Pas ici.
I'm too old for screwing in cars.
J'ai passé l'âge de baiser dans une voiture.
I don't like to hurry.
Je n'aime pas faire vite.
Why don't we go to Wichita and get a motel room?
Si on allait dans un motel à Wichita ?
I'm afraid to. I think my folks are watching me.
Non, mes parents me surveillent.
They might think we're gonna run off and get married.
Ils croiraient qu'on a fui pour se marier.
We'll do it when it's safe.
On le fera quand on pourra.
We got all summer.
On a tout l'été.
You turned roughneck.
Tu turbines ?
Gotta make a living so I can keep the pool hall open.
Faut bien, pour garder le billard.
When'd you get in?
Quand t'es arrivé ?
About 2. I thought I'd surprise you.
Vers 2 h. Je voulais te faire la surprise.
Is this yours?
Ta bagnole ?
Yeah, how about that? Thirty-eight thousand miles, and she runs like new.
Qu'est-ce que t'en dis ? 62 000 km, et comme neuve.
- Say, you want a beer? - Not me.
- Une bière ? - Non.
That's about all I eat for breakfast anymore.
Je prends plus que ça le matin.
Hey, sure is a nice car.
Chouette bagnole.
Yeah, I like to drive it so much, I thought I'd just drop home for the weekend.
Je suis venu rien que pour la conduire.
Yeah, you can't take too good care of a car like this.
Faut être aux petits soins pour elle.
I wash her every week.
Je la lave chaque semaine.
Oh, it looks great.
Elle est super.
Hear about Joe Bob?
T'as su pour Joe Bob ?
Yeah, I always knew he was crazy.
Je savais qu'il était pas net.
He didn't do nothing, except get her to take her underpants off.
Il lui a rien fait, à part lui faire enlever sa culotte.
- He's out of jail now. - Yeah.
Il est sorti de taule.
Are you still screwing that old lady?
Tu baises toujours la vieille ?
No. Yeah. I've been kind of busy.
Non. Si. Je suis très occupé.
I seen old Leroy last week.
J'ai rencontré Leroy.
He said he thought you and Jacy had been going together.
Paraît que tu sors avec Jacy.
Yeah, we have, a little.
Un petit peu.
She's been kind of bored, so once in a while, we go eat Mexican food.
Elle s'ennuie, alors on va bouffer mexicain, des fois.
Well, I hear that ain't all you been eating.
Tu bouffes pas que ça, paraît-il.
Well, whoever told you that don't know what he's talking about.
Celui qui t'a dit ça sait pas de quoi il parle.
Sure, I've been going with her. Why not?
On sort ensemble. Pourquoi pas ?
I never said I blamed you for it. I don't blame you much.
Je te reproche rien.
I never thought you'd do that. I thought we were best friends.
Mais je pensais qu'on était potes.
We are. What you so mad for? I never done nothing.
On l'est. Pourquoi t'es en rogne ? J'ai rien fait.
- Screwing my girl ain't nothing? - I ain't screwing her.
À part baiser ma nana ?
- Hell, you ain't! - Well, I ain't.
- Tu parles ! - Non.
- She's not your girl. - She is my girl!
- C'est pas ta nana. - Si !
You don't even live here anymore.
Tu vis même plus ici.
That don't make no difference! I'm getting her back.
Ça change rien ! Je la reprends.
She's gonna marry me one of these days.
Un jour, elle m'épousera.
- She won't. - We're meant to get married.
- Non. - On est faits pour se marier.
She's off to college soon.
Elle va à la fac.
I doubt I'll ever get to go with her again myself, once she gets off.
Je la verrai plus non plus quand elle s'en ira.
I never saw what it could hurt to go with her this summer though.
Y avait pas de mal à sortir avec elle.
- She's never gonna marry you. - She is! Don't tell me she won't!
- Elle t'épousera pas. - Arrête de dire ça !
She'd never let you screw her. That's for sure.
Elle voudra jamais te baiser.
Hell, I was just seeing how honest you was.
Je voulais voir si t'étais sincère.
Jacy would never let you screw her. You ain't that good a cocksman.
Jacy voudra jamais te baiser. T'es trop nul.
You never even screwed Charlene Duggs all that time.
T'as même pas baisé Charlene.
Course I didn't!
Non !
You know why?
Tu sais pourquoi ?
Because you had the pickup all the time Saturday night, that's why.
C'est toujours toi qui avais le camion !
Nobody could've screwed in the time I had.
J'en ai jamais eu le temps.
I could've screwed her in five minutes. I wouldn't need no pickup.
Je l'aurais baisée en 5 mn et sans camion.
What you talking about? We was in love.
N'importe quoi. On s'aimait.
Oh, you was. She likes me just as much as she ever liked you.
Toi, tu l'aimais. Je lui plais autant que toi.
- That's a lie. - I'll stay with her all night too.
Tu mens.
- She promised. - You won't either.
- Elle l'a promis. - Non.
I will. Why shouldn't I?
Pourquoi pas ?
She done told me you couldn't even do it that time in Wichita Falls.
Elle m'a dit que t'as rien fait à Wichita Falls.
What happened?
Que s'est-il passé ?
There's a lady in the waiting room. She sent you this.
Il y a une dame dehors qui vous envoie ça.
Could you tell her I'm asleep?
Dites-lui que je dors.
Please?
S'il vous plaît.
All right.
D'accord.
That too cold?
Pas trop froid ?
No, it's great.
Non, parfait.
Say, I hear Duane joined the Army.
Paraît que Duane s'est enrôlé.
Good place for him too.
C'est la place qu'il mérite.
He didn't mean to hit me with the bottle.
Il voulait pas me frapper avec la bouteille.
That boy's always had meanness in him.
Il a toujours eu un côté méchant.
Jacy's just the kind of girl that brings out the meanness in a man.
Et Jacy excite la méchanceté chez un homme.
She's just like her grandmother.
Comme sa grand-mère.
I hadn't ought to talk about them. We was all good friends once.
Je devrais pas dire ça. On a tous été copains.
Dan roughnecked with Gene Farrow.
Dan bossait avec Gene Farrow.
He and Lois used to live in this one-room place…
Gene et Lois avaient une piaule
… over the newspaper office.
au-dessus du journal.
Lois couldn't afford a flour sack, much less a mink.
Lois pouvait même pas s'acheter de la farine.
I've always had a soft spot for her, though.
J'ai toujours eu un faible pour elle.
Yeah, I wondered a lot of times what would've happened…
Je me suis souvent demandée où on en serait
… if my Dan had made the strikes that Gene made.
si mon Dan avait foncé comme Gene.
They offered that rig to him first.
C'est à lui qu'on a d'abord proposé le derrick.
Dan Morgan never took a chance in his life.
Dan a jamais su saisir une occase.
Do you wish y'all had made it?
Vous aimeriez avoir réussi ?
Sure, I wish we'd made it.
Ça, oui. Réussir.
I guess the Army won't take me now, I just got one good eye.
L'armée voudra pas de moi avec un seul œil.
You wanna go over to Korea and get yourself killed?
Tu veux te faire tuer en Corée ?
You ain't got your senses back yet, what few you ever had.
T'as pas retrouvé toute ta tête. Déjà qu'elle est pas grosse.
The café won't run itself. You rest up now.
Le café marche pas tout seul. Repose-toi.
Here's for the cheeseburger.
Tiens, pour le cheeseburger.
Okay, I'll bring your change when I bring your supper.
Je t'apporte la monnaie avec ton dîner.
Oh, come on in.
Entre.
Oh, I was so worried. I just had to see you.
Il fallait que je te voie.
Oh, I've been missing you.
Tu m'as manqué.
And I'm a lot better than I was. Here, sit down.
Ça va beaucoup mieux. Assieds-toi.
You can't believe how famous we are. We're all anybody talks about in town.
On est devenus célèbres. On ne parle que de nous.
- Yeah, I guess so. - I want us to get married.
- J'imagine. - Je veux qu'on se marie.
Get married?
Nous marier ?
Just as soon as you want to. Don't you want to?
Quand tu veux. Tu ne veux pas ?
I bet the town will be knocked for a loop. They'll never forget it.
Ça chamboulera la ville. Ils s'en souviendront.
Ain't you going to college?
Tu vas pas à la fac ?
I don't care about that. I love you, and that's more important.
Je t'aime, c'est ça qui compte.
You were so dear to fight for me.
Dire que tu t'es battu pour moi.
My folks won't like it, but we'll run off.
On s'enfuira à cause de mes vieux.
- They'll kill us. - No, they won't.
- Ils nous tueront. - Non.
- They'll kill me. - They'll get over it.
- Moi, si. - Ils s'y feront.
You're working for Daddy now anyway.
Tu travailles déjà pour papa.
Pretty soon, they'll love you just as much as I do.
Ils t'aimeront bientôt autant que moi.
Can we?
On le fait ?
Sure, I just hope I can see to drive.
Oui, pourvu que je puisse conduire.
Don't you worry. I can drive.
T'en fais pas, je conduirai.
Don't do that, Sonny.
Arrête, Sonny.
Why not?
Pourquoi ?
We're man and wife now. We can do anything.
On est mariés, on peut tout faire.
Not while I'm driving. I might have a wreck.
Pas pendant que je conduis.
Goodness. Wouldn't it be awful if Mama and Daddy got the police after us?
Ce serait terrible si papa et maman avaient averti la police.
- They don't even know where we are. - Well, I had to leave them a note.
- Ils savent pas où on est. - Je leur ai laissé un mot.
So they wouldn't be worried out of their mind.
Pour pas qu'ils s'angoissent.
Oh, you shouldn't have done that.
T'aurais pas dû.
I figured they'd have to know sometime.
Fallait bien qu'ils l'apprennent.
Well, what could they get us for?
Ils peuvent pas nous arrêter.
We got a right to get married. Ain't we?
On a le droit de se marier. Non ?
I guess so.
Je crois.
I wish you didn't have that stupid eye patch. It's really creepy.
Si seulement t'avais pas cet affreux pansement.
Oh, hey, I can take it off pretty soon.
Je l'enlèverai bientôt.
About two hours, will be Lake Texoma. Have a room to ourself.
Dans 2 h, on sera à Lake Texoma. Dans notre chambre.
My goodness! You're sitting so close, I can barely drive.
Tu me serres trop, j'ai du mal à conduire.
Oh, goodness.
Mon Dieu !
Howdy.
Salut.
- What part of Texas y'all from? - Anarene.
- D'où vous venez ? - D'Anarene.
Newlyweds, ain't you?
Jeunes mariés, hein ?
Y'all better follow me on in. I think somebody's looking for you.
Suivez-moi. Y a quelqu'un qui vous cherche.
We got a right to get married. How can you arrest us?
On a le droit. Vous pouvez pas nous arrêter.
I ain't arresting you. I just want you to come with me.
Je vous arrête pas. Je vous demande de me suivre.
I don't know what your rights are.
Je connais pas vos droits.
I guess we better follow him, honey.
Il vaut mieux le suivre.
I'll just be heartbroken if my folks have done this.
J'aurai le cœur brisé si c'est mes parents.
You think I worked hard so my daughter could end up in a pool hall?
J'ai pas bossé pour qu'elle finisse dans un billard !
- We was gonna get another apartment. - I'll bet!
- On allait prendre un appart. - Tu parles !
Where are your car keys?
Tes clés de voiture ?
It's a hell of a note! Just a hell of a note!
Quant au mot, parlons-en !
- Oh, shut up and take her home. - You bet I will!
- Tais-toi et ramène-la. - Et comment !
You take her car. As far as I'm concerned, he can walk!
Prends sa voiture. Lui, qu'il rentre à pied !
- Not much of a wedding night, huh? - Nope.
Une nuit de noces un peu triste, hein ?
Not much of one.
Plutôt.
Here. Have a little drink of bourbon. It'll pick you up.
Bois un peu de bourbon. Ça te remontera.
Take all of it. I'm gonna drive.
Finis-le, je conduis.
You won't believe this…
Tu vas pas me croire,
… but you're lucky we got you clear of her quick as we did.
mais tu as de la chance qu'on t'ait sorti de ce pétrin.
You'd have been a lot better off staying with Ruth Popper.
Tu aurais mieux fait de rester avec Ruth.
Does everybody know about that?
Tout le monde est au courant ?
Course.
Naturellement.
Sounded like a good deal to me, kiddo. Shouldn't let Jacy turn your head.
Je trouvais ça bien. Laisser Jacy te tourner la tête !
Well, she's prettier.
Elle est plus jolie.
I guess I shouldn't have, though. I guess I treated her terrible.
Mais j'aurais pas dû. J'ai été dur avec elle, hein ?
Guess you did.
Tu peux le dire.
Sure weren't out of Texas very long.
On n'a pas quitté le Texas longtemps.
Well, Oklahoma's not much of an improvement.
L'Oklahoma ne vaut guère mieux.
It's not the same now.
C'est plus pareil, maintenant.
Nothing's really been right since Sam the Lion died.
Ça tourne plus rond depuis la mort de Sam.
No, it hasn't.
Ça tourne plus rond.
Oh, God.
Flûte…
I get sad if I think of Sam for long.
Ça me rend triste de penser à Sam.
Did you know he had beautiful hands?
Tu savais qu'il avait de belles mains ?
I guess you liked him, didn't you?
Vous l'aimiez bien, pas vrai ?
I guess everybody did.
Tout le monde l'aimait bien.
Well, I'll tell you, it was different with me, Sonny.
C'était autre chose, dans mon cas.
I loved him.
Je l'aimais.
He loved me too.
Il m'aimait, lui aussi.
Are you the one he'd take swimming…
C'est vous qu'il emmenait nager
… out at the tank?
à l'étang ?
He told you about that, huh?
Il te l'a raconté ?
Yeah, I was the one.
Oui, c'était moi.
I guess if it wasn't for Sam, I'd…
Je crois que sans Sam…
… just about have missed it. Whatever it is.
j'aurais loupé l'essentiel, s'il existe.
I'd have been one of them amity types that thinks that…
J'aurais été une de ces braves femmes qui croient…
… playing bridge is about the best thing that life has to offer.
que la belle vie, c'est jouer au bridge.
Old Sam the Lion.
Bon vieux Sam le Lion.
Sam the Lion. Nobody knows where he got that name. I gave it to him.
Personne ne sait que c'est moi qui lui ai donné ce nom.
One night…
Un soir…
… it just came to me.
ça m'est venu tout seul.
He was so pleased.
Il en a été ravi.
I was 22 years old then.
J'avais 22 ans, à l'époque.
Can you imagine?
Tu te rends compte ?
I tell you, Sonny…
C'est affreux
… it's terrible to only meet one man in your whole life…
de ne rencontrer qu'un homme qui sache ce que tu vaux.
Just terrible.
Affreux.
I've looked too.
J'ai cherché.
You wouldn't believe how I've looked.
Si tu savais comme j'ai cherché.
- Well, now I know why Sam liked you. - Loved me.
Maintenant, je sais pourquoi Sam vous aimait bien.
Loved you, I mean.
Vous aimait.
Do you?
Vraiment ?
I can kind of see what he saw in you too.
Moi, je vois ce qu'il a vu en toi.
Nope. I'll just go on home.
Non, je rentre.
Go on. Get out.
Descends.
Think I could—? Think I could learn to drink?
Vous croyez que j'apprendrai à boire ?
You might. Better keep on practising.
Ça se pourrait. Entraîne-toi.
That Logan boy's a quarterback, now, ain't he?
C'est un sacré arrière, ce Logan !
Boy, we've finally got us a team!
On a enfin une équipe !
Didn't back in your day, did they, Sonny?
La défense clochait, de ton temps.
No, we wasn't much good.
On valait pas grand-chose.
Well, you just never learned the fundamentals.
Il vous manquait les bases.
You know, blocking and tackling.
Le blocage, le plaquage.
Not like this team.
C'est pas comme eux.
- When was it you graduated? - Last year.
- T'as eu ton diplôme ? - L'an dernier.
You don't mean it.
Sans blague !
Seems like longer than that since you and old Duane played ball.
Ça paraît loin, quand Duane et toi vous jouiez.
I seen Duane a while ago.
J'ai revu Duane.
He's home on leave, wearing his uniform.
Il a une perme. En uniforme.
I ain't seen him yet.
Je l'ai pas encore vu.
- How are you, Chester? - Fine, coach.
- Comment va, Chester ? - Bien.
Now, listen, see if we can't stretch that goddamn thing a little.
Va voir si on peut faire une entourloupe.
You know a man never ought to cheat, unless it's for a good cause.
On doit pas tricher, sauf si c'est pour une bonne cause.
He's a good old boy, ain't he?
Un brave type, hein ?
Hi, Mrs Jackson.
Bonjour, Mme Jackson.
Duane here?
Duane est là ?
That's his car out there, ain't it? He's here if he ain't walked off.
C'est sa voiture, non ? Il est là s'il est pas sorti.
Hi, how you been?
Salut, ça va ?
Oh, pretty good.
Plutôt bien.
I been thinking all week that I'd run into you.
Toute la semaine, j'ai pensé te voir.
I heard you was going off to Korea.
Paraît que tu pars pour la Corée.
Thought I'd get over here and see you before you got off.
Je voulais te voir avant ton départ.
Glad you did. I'm taking the bus out early in the morning.
Ça me fait plaisir. Je prends le car demain matin.
Want to go to the picture show?
Tu veux aller au cinéma ?
Miss Mosey's having to close it. Tonight's the last night.
Mlle Mosey ferme. C'est le dernier soir.
Yeah, might as well go.
Oui, bonne idée.
Hate to miss the last night. Take the Mercury.
Je veux pas rater ça. En voiture.
Be the last chance I'll have to drive it for a while.
Je la conduirai plus pendant longtemps.
Ready, Matthew?
Prêt, Matthew ?
All ready.
Oui.
Take them to Missouri, Matt.
Emmène-les au Missouri.
- That was a good movie. - Yeah.
Un bon film.
Seen it here before once.
Je l'avais déjà vu.
Why don't we run over to Wichita and drink some beer?
On va prendre une bière à Wichita ?
Okay. I got lots of time till morning.
D'accord. J'ai le temps jusqu'à demain.
Sure.
Ouais.
Well, so long, Miss Mosey.
Au revoir, Mlle Mosey.
Sorry you're closing the show.
Dommage que vous fermiez.
Nobody wants to come to shows no more.
Plus personne va au cinéma.
Kid baseball in the summer, television all the time.
Le base-ball, l'été. La télé, tout le temps.
Sam had lived, I believe we could've kept it going.
Si Sam avait été là, on aurait pu continuer.
But I just didn't have the know-how.
Mais je savais pas y faire.
Won't be much to do in town with the picture show closed.
Y aura plus grand-chose à faire sans cinéma.
Well, so long.
Au revoir.
You watch out now, overseas.
Fais attention à toi, là-bas.
Sure weren't no women around.
Les nanas ont pas abondé.
I guess the next piece of ass I get will be yellow.
Ma prochaine, ce sera une jaune.
I wish I was going with you.
J'aimerais partir avec toi.
Why don't you take care of the car for me?
Tu me gardes ma bagnole ?
Your ma don't need it?
Ta mère en a pas besoin ?
I wouldn't want her driving it. No better than she can drive.
Je veux pas qu'elle la conduise. Gare, avec elle.
Help her take the groceries home if you got time.
Emmène-la faire ses courses.
You ever—?
T'as…
You ever hear from Jacy?
des nouvelles de Jacy ?
No, not a thing.
Non, jamais.
She don't get home much. Ain't been back to town since August.
Elle rentre pas souvent. On l'a pas vue depuis août.
I guess she just stays in Dallas all the time.
Elle doit rester à Dallas.
Yeah, probably does.
Sans doute.
I guess there's lots to do down in Dallas.
Y a de quoi faire à Dallas.
I ain't over her yet, you know.
Je l'ai pas encore oubliée.
I ain't over her yet.
Pas encore oubliée.
It's the damnedest thing.
C'est dingue, ça.
That's the only reason—
C'est seulement pour ça qu'on s'est engueulés, nous deux.
Hey, reckon she likes it down in Dallas?
Elle doit aimer Dallas.
It's hard to say. Maybe she does.
Va savoir, peut-être.
Reckon you and her would've got it all straighted out if I hadn't butted in?
Vous auriez fini ensemble si j'avais pas été là.
No, they'd have annulled me too, even if we had.
J'aurais pas pu l'épouser, moi non plus.
Y'all never even got into the motel?
Vous êtes même pas allés au motel ?
… better get on before we both freeze.
J'y vais avant qu'on gèle.
Here are the keys.
Tiens, les clés.
- So long, buddy. - So long, Duane.
Salut, mon pote.
Be careful.
Fais gaffe.
I'll take care of the Mercury.
Je me charge de la caisse.
I'll see you in a year or two if I don't get shot.
À dans un an ou deux, si on me tue pas.
- The wind is blowing real hard. - He was right out in front of that station.
- Le vent est fort. - Il était devant la station.
Christ, the trucker didn't have a chance.
Le conducteur ne pouvait rien faire.
Yeah, he's out here all the time doing something.
Il est tout le temps là.
I can see it wasn't your fault.
C'était pas ta faute.
The sand was blowing. I never noticed him.
Avec le sable partout,
Figured nobody'd be in the street.
J'ai vu personne.
What was he doing out there carrying that broom?
Qu'est-ce qu'il faisait là ?
He weren't doing nothing. Just a simple-minded kid.
Rien du tout. C'était un simple d'esprit.
- Never had no sense. - Wasn't your fault.
- Il divaguait. - T'y es pour rien.
Hell, no, mister! I can see that.
Non, ça se voit.
He was just a dumb old kid.
C'était un idiot.
Didn't know enough to keep his ass out of the cold.
Il pensait même pas à rester au chaud.
Let's go to the café. Ain't had breakfast.
Allons au café, j'ai rien bouffé.
I'd still like to know what he was doing with that broom.
Je me demande ce qu'il faisait avec ce balai.
He was sweeping, you sons of bitches!
Il balayait, salopards !
He was sweeping!
Il balayait !
Y'all got some crazy kids in this town, if you ask me.
Y a pas mal de dingues, par ici.
Could I have a cup of coffee with you?
Je peux prendre un café avec toi ?
I guess.
Pourquoi pas ?
I'm sorry. I'm still in my bathrobe.
Excuse-moi, je suis en robe de chambre.
What am I doing apologising to you?
Pourquoi je m'excuse ?
Why am I always apologising to you, you little bastard?
Pourquoi je m'excuse toujours, salaud ?
Three months I've apologised to you without you even being here!
Trois mois que je m'excuse, et t'es même pas là !
I haven't done anything wrong. Why can't I quit apologising?
J'ai rien fait de mal. Pourquoi j'arrête pas ?
You ought to be sorry!
C'est à toi de t'excuser !
I wouldn't still be in my bathrobe if not for you.
Si je t'avais pas connu, je me serais déjà habillée.
You're the one made me quit caring if I got dressed or not!
Si je me fiche d'être habillée ou pas, c'est à cause de toi !
Just because your friend got killed…
Parce que ton copain est mort,
… you want me to forget what you did and make it all right.
tu veux que j'oublie tout et que ça s'arrange.
I'm not sorry for you.
Tu me fais pas pitié.
You'd have left Billy too, just like you left me.
Tu aurais quitté Billy, comme moi.
I bet you left him plenty of nights…
Je parie que tu le plaquais…
… whenever Jacy whistled.
dès que Jacy te sifflait.
I wouldn't treat a dog that way.
Il valait moins qu'un chien.
You thought I was so old and ugly, you didn't owe me any explanation.
Parce que je suis vieille, tu me devais pas d'explication ?
You didn't need to be careful of me.
T'avais pas à me respecter ?
There was nothing I could do about you and her, so why be careful?
Je pouvais rien contre vous. Pourquoi m'éviter ?
You didn't love me.
Tu ne m'aimais pas.
Look at me.
Regarde-moi.
Can't you even look at me?
Tu peux même pas me regarder ?
See?
Tu vois ?
Shouldn't have come here.
T'aurais pas dû venir.
I'm around that corner now.
J'ai passé le cap.
You've ruined it.
Tu as tout gâché.
It's lost completely.
Y a plus rien, fini.
Just your needing me won't make it come back.
Ça reviendra pas parce que t'as besoin de moi.
Never you mind, honey.
Ne t'en fais pas, chéri.
Never you mind.
Ne t'en fais pas.